VASANTHKUMAR PORCHEZIYAN

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER / TEAM LEAD

📞 +91 9042481090 🛮 vasanthporcheziyan@gmail.com 🛮 in in/vasanthkumarporcheziyan

SUMMARY SKILLS

Creative Senior Software Engineer offering 6 years of experience. Enthusiastic about developing forward-thinking solutions to tomorrow's productivity problems. Resourceful and adaptable approach to challenges. Decisive leader and reliable team builder with results-focused and driven approach. Proficient in End - End (Full stack) and Agile/Scrum methodology

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Ducen IT Pvt Ltd | Chennai | Jan 2019 - Present

- Trained and mentored junior developers and engineers, teaching skills in required technologies and working to improve overall team performance.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings with Project managers and Product owners and delivered within deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Designed and developed forward-thinking systems that meet user needs and improve productivity.
- Worked as Analance Product Specialist at Philippines for 6 months.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Ducen IT Pvt Ltd | Chennai | Oct 2017 - Dec 2018

- Gathered data on integration issues and vulnerabilities and reported all findings, including improvement recommendations.
- Exhibited strong technical aptitude and application expertise resulting in optimized performance, continuous improvement recommendations and product innovation.
- Improved system performance by making proactive adjustments and resolving bugs.
- · Suggested improvements to team and project workflow.

PROGRAMMER ANALYST

Cognizant Technology Solutions | Chennai | Aug 2016 - Sept 2017

- Collaborated with cross-functional development team members to analyze potential system solutions based on evolving requirements.
- Developed new product elements such as image recognition, hand writing recognition, audio, video and device-to-device communication.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Sofist India | Chennai | May 2014 - Jul 2016

- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement
- Collaborated on all stages of system development lifecycle, from requirements gathering to production releases.

Angular 6+	
JavaScript	
C#	
Web Services	
DotNet Core	
DotNet MVC	
MongoDB	
MS-SQL Server	
Micro Services	
Design Patterns	
GitLab	
Jenkins	
DevExtreme / Dev Express	
SonarQube	
Business Intelligence	
Aglie	

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certificate of achievement on Artificial Intelligence
- Certificate of achievement on Industrial IoT Google Cloud Platform
- Contributed for CMMI re-appraisal for Development and release area

AWARDS & HONORS

- Received an Spot Excellence Award from Ducen IT Pvt Ltd
- Build and trained new team at Philippines
- Handled project individually

PROJECTS

ANALANCE - BI

Ducen IT Pvt Ltd | Team size - 45 | Chennai | Oct 2016 - Present

Business intelligence software with sophisticated functionalities that enables organizations to meet its changing needs, and a firm can customize and brand everything so that they can maintain complete control over the end-user-experience. Analance advanced analytics capabilities can be leveraged for deeper insights and making smart data-informed decisions through advanced analytics that go beyond traditional analytics, and big data analysis that connects and gain insights from big data sources. Analance BI and Reporting and Data discovery feature ensure decisions are made with meaningful insights, and its collaboration capability makes sure that collaboration decisions are possible.

CORELOGIC

Cognizant Technology Solutions | Team size - 30 | Chennai | Aug 2016 - Sept 2017

A web based application which provides solution to extract the required data's from documents based on FIPS County and Type of document uploaded. The document should cross certain level of stages to get processed and then user can finally get the extracted values in UI.

TAPPZ

Sofist India | Team size - 1 | Chennai | May 2016 - Jul 2016

Tappz project is native application to get right apps for users from google play store. Tappz includes features like two level category grouping, cities where those apps service are available so on. I have used HTML with Jquery and KnockOutJS for front-end and NodeJS to retrieve data's.

THE LAW WEEKLY

Sofist India | Team size - 3 | Chennai | Feb 2016 - May 2016

A complete Law based website, main aim of the project is to make easy interface and uses of law cases for customers through online. I have used SQL Server 2012 to hold data's. The application is created under DevExtreme components integrated with MVC 4.

CTC LIBRARY

Sofist India | Team size - 3 | Chennai | Nov 2015 - Jan 2016

A complete Law based website, main aim of the project is to make easy interface and uses of law cases for customers through online. I have used SQL Server 2012 to hold data's. The application is created under DevExtreme components integrated with MVC 4.

EDUCATION

B.E (Electronics and Communcation Engineering) (Sept 2009 - May 2013)

T.J. Institute of Technology | 6.4 CGPA | Chennai

H.S.C (Jun 2008 - Mar 2009)

P.C.K.G Govt Hr. Sec. School | 73.5% | Chennai

S.S.L.C (Jun 2006 - Mar 2007)

P.C.K.G Govt. Hr. Sec. School | 68% | Chennai

LANGUAGES

English (Advanced)

Tamil (Expert)

Tagalog (Beginner)

HOBBIES



Coding Challenges

Sketching



Learning **New Things**



Table tennis

PERSONAL DETAILS

Address

32/14, Kalaimagal street, Choolaimedu

PRODUCTWIZ

Sofist India | Team size - 6 | Chennai | Jul 2014 - Nov 2015

Complete ecommerce shopping system with following features. The admin module and client side module are created using DEVEPXRESS tool. We have used DEVEPXRESSASP.Net for admin module and DEVEXTREME for client side module. Administration system to easily update all product details, prices, pictures, stock details and other information online.Manage Customer Accounts. Manage Wish list. Customer Reviews & Rating. Manage categories and products. Manage Product options and related products. Advanced pricing algorithms. Order and Invoice history. Take payments online using PayPal. Shopping cart system to allow easy purchase of products. Automatic email notification of orders. Full checkout procedure. Fast and friendly quick search and advanced search features. Reports of site visits, pages viewed, most viewed products, and most ordered products and most viewed categories.

VINATHI FOUNDATION

Sofist India | Team size - 1 | Chennai | May 2014 - Jul 2014

Vinathi foundation is a web based project. I used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript languages in my project. I had created and controlled the layout of the web page through CSS and JavaScript.